Register of the Fritz Machlup Papers, 1911-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL, 1933-1983
  - Nourse, Edwin G. (Brookings Institution), 1941-1967 (Folder 18)
  - Nuffield College, 1972-1976 (Folder 19)
  - Nussbaumer, Adolf, 1979 (Folder 20)
  - Oberlin College, 1946 (Folder 21)
  - Occidental College, 1941 (Folder 22)
  - O'Connor, Herbert R., 1949-1950 (Folder 23)
  - Odegaard, Charles E., 1971 (Folder 24)
  - Offen, Elly, 1941-1974 (Folder 25)
  - Ohio University, 1971 (Folder 26)
  - Ohlin, Bertil, 1954-1979 (Folder 27)
  - Oklahoma State University, 1961-1971 (Folder 28)
  - Oliver, Henry, 1954 (Folder 29)
  - Ooms, Casper W., 1953 (Folder 30)
  - Oort, Conrad J., 1975-1976 (Folder 31)
  - Opie, Redvers, 1942-1965 (Folder 32)
  - Oppenheim, Paul, 1967 (Folder 33)
  - Ordo (Ursula Kupper, Fritz Meyer, Hans Willgerodt), 1948-1978 (Folder 34)
  - Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development, 1970-1982 (Folder 35)
  - Ossola, Rinaldo, 1964-1974 (Folder 36)
  - Osterreichische Akademie fur Fuhrungskrafte, 1973 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Osterreichische Hochschulerschaft, 1975 (Folder 2)
  - Osterreichische Nationalbank (Ferdinand Hain, Heinz Kienzl, Hans Kloss, Stephan Koren, Philipp Rieger, Ludwig Seiberl), 1967-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Osterreichische Volkswirt, Der, 1934 (Folder 4)
  - Osterreichisches Institut fur Wirtschaftsforschung (Hans Seidel), 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Osterreichisches Komitee der Freunde des Europaischen Forum Alpbach, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - Osteuropa-Institut an der Freien Universitat Berlin, 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Oxford University Press, 1938-1954 (Folder 8)
  - Ozaki, Eiji, 1970-1972 (Folder 9)
  - Paakkanen, Jouko, 1965-1970 (Folder 10)
  - Pakistan Institute of Development Economics, 1974-1982 (Folder 11)
  - Pakistan Society of Development Economists, 1983 (Folder 12)
  - Palyi, M., 1935 (Folder 13)
  - Papandreou, Andreas G., 1962-1967 (Folder 14)
  - Papi, G. Ugo, 1961-1982 (Folder 15)
  - Park, Julian (University of Buffalo), 1946-1950 (Folder 16)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1936-1939 (Folder 17)
  - Patinkin, Don, 1966-1977 (Folder 18)
  - Paton, William A., 1964-1966 (Folder 19)
  - Patterson, Gardner, 1950-1969 (Folder 20)
  - Peacock, Alan T., 1953-1973 (Folder 21)
  - Pegrum, Dudley F., 1940 (Folder 22)
  - Penrose, Edith T. Includes correspondence with David Denhardt
    - 1955-1957 (Folder 23)
    - 1958 (Folder 24)
    - 1959-1963 (Folder 25)
    - 1964-1970 (Folder 26)
    - 1971-1982 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Perkins, J. O. N. (University of Melbourne), 1970 (Folder 2)
  - Perlman, Mark (Journal of Economic Literature), 1958-1982 (Folder 3)
  - Perroux, Francois, 1937-1979 (Folder 4)
  - Perry, J. E., 1938-1939 (Folder 5)
  - Peston, Maurice, 1968-1971 (Folder 6)
  - Peterson, Peter G., 1971 (Folder 7)
  - Peterson, William H., 1964-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Petshek, Kirk R., 1952 (Folder 9)
  - Petshek, Kurt, 1941 (Folder 10)
  - Pfaundler, Wolfgang, 1981. Includes holograph on the Sparkasse Innsbruck-Hall (Folder 11)
  - Pfister, Bernhard, 1959-1963 (Folder 12)
  - Pfleiderer, Otto, 1963-1982. Includes correspondence with Wilhelm Seuss (Folder 13)
  - Pfouts, R. W., 1966 (Folder 14)
  - Phelps, Clyde William, 1938-1941 (Folder 15)
  - Phelps, Edmund S., 1977 (Folder 16)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1940-1972 (Folder 17)
  - Phillips, Almarin, 1962-1973 (Folder 18)
  - Phillips, C. A., 1945 (Folder 19)
  - Piatier, A., 1953-1955 (Folder 20)
  - Pick, Franz, 1953-1958 (Folder 21)
  - Piffl-Percevic, Theodor, 1965-1966 (Folder 22)
  - Pirou, Gaetan, 1938 (Folder 23)
  - Plant, Arnold, 1958 (Folder 24)
  - Polack, Jacques J. (International Monetary Fund), 1949-1980 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Politico, 1967 (Folder 2)
  - Popescu, Oreste, 1958-1962 (Folder 3)
  - Popper, Sir Karl, 1955-1982 (Folder 4)
  - Porat, Marc, 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Posten, M. M., 1955-1957 (Folder 6)
  - Posthuma, Suardus, 1963-1966 (Folder 7)
  - Praeger Publishers, 1971-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Predohl, Andreas, 1955-1966 (Folder 9)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1937-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Presse, 1967 (Folder 11)
  - Pribram, Karl and Edith, 1966-1979 (Folder 12)
  - Price, Derek J. de Solla, 1977-1980 (Folder 13)
  - Princeton University, 1947-1982 (Folder 14)
  - Princeton University Press (Herbert S. Bailey, Jr.), 1962-1983 (Folder 15-16)
  - Prindl, Andreas R., 1972-1976 (Folder 17)
  - Probst, Kurt, 1949-1950 (Folder 18)
  - Prosi, Gerhard, 1966-1980 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Puffer, Claude E., 1939-1942 (Folder 2)
  - Putz, Theodor, 1971 (Folder 3)
  - Quandt, Richard E., 1967-1974 (Folder 4)
  - Quarterly Journal of Economics (A. E. Monroe, Frank W. Taussig), 1934-1971 (Folder 5)
  - Raff, Morton S., 1956-1957 (Folder 6)
  - Raj, K. N., 1955-1956 (Folder 7)
  - Rao, V. K. R. V. (University of Delhi), 1955 (Folder 8)
  - Rappard, William W., 1950-1955 (Folder 9)
  - Rasminsky, Louis, 1967-1968 (Folder 10)
  - Ratner, Sidney, 1970-1981 (Folder 11)
  - Reader's Digest, 1941-1953 (Folder 12)
  - Recktenwald, Horst Claus, 1978 (Folder 13)
  - Reed, Harold L., 1936 (Folder 14)
  - Rees, Albert E., 1965 (Folder 15)
  - Reisman, George, 1978 (Folder 16)
  - Rescher, Nicholas, 1981 (Folder 17)
  - Reuss, Henry S., 1962-1982 (Folder 18)
  - Review of Economics and Statistics (Aaron Goldstein, Hendrik S. Houthakker, Joseph B. Hubbard), 1934-1973 (Folder 19)
  - Revista de economia politica, 1958-1971 (Folder 20)
  - Reynolds, Lloyd G., 1942-1981 (Folder 21)
  - Rheinstein, Max, 1939 (Folder 22)
  - Riboud, Jacques (Revue politique et parlementaire), 1976-1979 (Folder 23)
  - Richard D. Irwin, Inc., 1952-1968 (Folder 24)
  - Richter, R., 1967-1971 (Folder 25)
  - Rickett, Denis H. F., 1966-1974 (Folder 26)
  - Riegle, Donald W., Jr., 1979 (Folder 27)
  - Riesman, David, 1938-1980 (Folder 28)
  - Rinehart and Company, 1952 (Folder 29)
  - Riron Keizaigaku, 1955-1956 (Folder 30)
  - Rittershausen, Professor, 1934 (Folder 31)
  - Rivista internazionale di scienze economiche e commerciali, 1955-1976 (Folder 32)
  - Robbins, Lord Lionel, 1934-1979 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Robertson, Sir Dennis, 1936-1963 (Folder 2)
  - Robinson, Sir Austin and Joan, 1934-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Robinson, Roland I., 1949 (Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1975 (Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Foundation. Includes activities and progress reports
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 6)
    - 1934 (Folder 7)
    - 1935-1948 (Folder 8)
    - 1950-1982 (Folder 9)
  - Roll, Eric and Freda, 1940-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Roosa, Robert V., 1949-1975 (Folder 11)
  - Roper, Burkhardt, 1955 (Folder 12)
  - Rose, K., 1963 (Folder 13)
  - Rosegger, Gerhard, 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Rosenstein-Rodan, Paul N., 1938-1979 (Folder 15)
  - Rosovsky, Henry, 1976 (Folder 16)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., 1952-1958 (Folder 17)
  - Rothschild, Kurt, 1973-1978 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Rotraut Pleyer, Barbara, 1965 (Folder 2)
  - Roucek, Joseph S., 1947 (Folder 3)
  - Rougier, Lucy, 1981-1982 (Folder 4)
  - Row, Peterson and Company, 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Rowen, Hobart, 1975 (Folder 6)
  - Rowley, Charles K., 1967-1972 (Folder 7)
  - Royal Academy of Sciences, 1969-1977 (Folder 8)
  - Royal Economic Society, 1934-1959 (Folder 9)
  - Rueff, Jacques and Christiane, 1963-1979 (Folder 10)
  - Ruff, Gunther H., 1967 (Folder 11)
  - Ruhr-Universitat Bochum, 1968 (Folder 12)
  - Rusch, William H., 1946-1953 (Folder 13)
  - Rustow, Hanns-Joachim, 1969-1980 (Folder 14)
  - St. Martin's Press, 1968-1973 (Folder 15)
  - Sakai, Shozaburo, 1955-1963 (Folder 16)
  - Salant, Walter S.
    - 1963-1968 (Folder 17)
    - 1969-1978 (Folder 18)
  - Salant, William A., 1942-1966 (Folder 19)
  - Salin, Edgar, 1951-1973 (Folder 20)
  - Salin, Pascal, 1971-1973 (Folder 21)
  - Sametz, Arnold W., 1973 (Folder 22)
  - Samuels, Len H., 1966 (Folder 23)
  - Samuels, Warren J., 1980-1982 (Folder 24)
  - Samuelson, Paul A., 1941-1980 (Folder 25)
  - Sargeant, Howland W., 1948 (Folder 26)
  - Sawers, David, 1964-1968 (Folder 27)
  - Scharrer, Hans-Eckart, 1973-1975 (Folder 28)
  - Schelbert-Syfrig, Heidi, 1966-1970 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Schiff, Eric
    - 1934-1968 (Folder 2)
    - 1969-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Schleiminger, Gunther, 1972-1975 (Folder 4)
  - Schlittler Silva, Helio, 1954-1958 (Folder 5)
  - Schmidt, Emerson P., 1944-1948 (Folder 6)
  - Schmitz, Wolfgang, 1968-1974 (Folder 7)
  - Schmolders, Gunter, 1969-1982 (Folder 8)
  - Schmookler, Jacob, 1950-1961 (Folder 9)
  - Schneider, Erich and Erna, 1947-1975 (Folder 10)
  - Scholarly Publishing, 1982 (Folder 11)
  - Schreier, Fritz, 1942-1943 (Folder 12)
  - Schuchman, Robert M., 1965-1966 (Folder 13)
  - Schultz, Henry, 1935 (Folder 14)
  - Schultz, Theodore W., 1961-1983 (Folder 15)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph A., 1934-1949 (Folder 16)
  - Schutz, Ilse, 1960-1982 (Folder 17)
  - Schwartz, Louis B., 1953 (Folder 18)
  - Schweitzer, Arthur, 1940 (Folder 19)
  - Science, 1959-1983 (Folder 20)
  - Scitovsky, Tibor, 1951-1973 (Folder 21)
  - Sebba, Gregor, 1938-1964 (Folder 22)
  - Seidenfus, Hellmuth Stefan, 1977-1982 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Seidl, Christian, 1982 (Folder 2)
  - Sergeant, Jack, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Shaw, Edward S. (Stanford University), 1940-1969 (Folder 4)
  - Shenoy, Sudha R., 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Shibata, Hiroshi, 1972 (Folder 6)
  - Shibata, Kei, 1954-1962 (Folder 7)
  - Shimazu, Ryoji, 1955-1960 (Folder 8)
  - Shinjo, Hiroshi, 1955-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Shinkai, Yoichi, 1970 (Folder 10)
  - Shinohara, Miyohei, 1955-1977 (Folder 11)
  - Shionoya, Tsukumo, 1962 (Folder 12)
  - Shorter, Bari and Fred, 1963-1964 (Folder 13)
  - Shortliffe, J. Melbourne, 1939-1941 (Folder 14)
  - Shoup, Carl, 1946 (Folder 15)
  - Shryock, Rheva, 1963 (Folder 16)
  - Shubik, Martin, 1975 (Folder 17)
  - Sievers, Allen M., 1961 (Folder 18)
  - Siglo Veintiuno Editores, 1972-1982 (Folder 19)
  - Simon, Hans, 1943 (Folder 20)
  - Simon, Harold A., 1963 (Folder 21)
  - Simon, Julian L., 1967-1983 (Folder 22)
  - Simon, Walter B., 1969 (Folder 23)
  - Simons, Henry, 1945 (Folder 24)
  - Simpson, Paul, 1940-1953 (Folder 25)
  - Singer, Rudolf and Lisl, 1938-1982 (Folder 26)
  - Singer, Walther, 1937-1939 (Folder 27)
  - Sirc, Ljubo, 1970-1971 (Folder 28)
  - Skandinaviska Enskilda Banken, 1969-1973 (Folder 29)
  - Skiba, Gunther, 1967-1968 (Folder 30)
  - Slater, J. E., 1956 (Folder 31)
  - Slichter, Sumner H., 1948-1959 (Folder 32)
  - Smith, Bradford B., 1937-1939 (Folder 33)
  - Smith, Leroy O., 1947-1948 (Folder 34)
  - Smith, Newlin, 1939-1946 (Folder 35)
  - Smith, Robert S., 1968 (Folder 36)
  - Smith, Warren L., 1954-1965 (Folder 37)
  - Smithies, Arthur, 1961-1947 (Folder 38)
  - Socher, Karl, 1977-1978 (Folder 39)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1938-1982 (Folder 40)
  - Sohmen, Egon and Regine, 1961-1981 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Solo, Robert, 1952-1982 (Folder 2)
  - Solomon, Frederic, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Solomon, Robert, 1966-1982 (Folder 4)
  - Solow, Robert M., 1962-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Somers, Harold M., 1939-1966 (Folder 6)
  - Sommer, Louise, 1938-1958 (Folder 7)
  - Sonntag, Philipp, 1982 (Folder 8)
  - Southern Economic Association, 1954-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Southern Economic Journal (Gus T. Schwennig, William H. Wesson, Jr.), 1955-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Southern Methodist University, 1957-1962 (Folder 11)
  - Southwestern University, 1964 (Folder 12)
  - Sowell, Thomas, 1975 (Folder 13)
  - Spengler, Joseph J., 1945-1978 (Folder 14)
  - Spiegel, Henry W., 1940-1941 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Spitzer, Leo, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Springer-Verlag, 1936-1958 (Folder 3)
  - Sproul, Allan, 1961-1968 (Folder 4)
  - Staehle, Hans, 1947 (Folder 5)
  - Stanford University, 1934-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Starbuck, William H., 1973 (Folder 7)
  - State of New York Commission on Medical Care, 1945 (Folder 8)
  - Stedman, John C., 1961-1981 (Folder 9)
  - Stein, Josef and Margarete, 1934-1941 (Folder 10)
  - Stein, Richard, 1938-1945 (Folder 11)
  - Steiner, Elise, 1981-1982 (Folder 12)
  - Stettner, Leonora L., 1948 (Folder 13)
  - Stevenson, R. A., 1937 (Folder 14)
  - Stigler, George J., 1938-1982 (Folder 15)
  - Stiglitz, Joseph E., 1978 (Folder 16)
  - Stocking, George W., 1948-1964 (Folder 17)
  - Stoddard, George D. (University of Illinois), 1950 (Folder 18)
  - Stolper, Wolfgang F., 1940-1953 (Folder 19)
  - Stone, J. R. N., 1948-1952 (Folder 20)
  - Stone, Sir Richard, 1978 (Folder 21)
  - Streeten, Paul P., 1955-1971 (Folder 22)
  - Streissler, Erich and Monika, 1962-1978 (Folder 23)
  - Strigl, Richard von, 1934 (Folder 24)
  - Strotz, Robert H., 1971 (Folder 25)
  - Studi in Onore di Gustavo del Vecchio (Federico Caffe), 1959-1961 (Folder 26)
  - Studi in Onore di Marco Fanno (Tullio Bagiotti), 1963-1965 (Folder 27)
  - Sturmey, S. G., 1963 (Folder 28)
  - Stutzel, Wolfgang, 1973-1974 (Folder 29)
  - Sulzbach, Walter, 1937-1948 (Folder 30)
  - Sumner, John Duncan, 1938-1943 (Folder 31)
  - Sun, 1950-1957 (Folder 32)
  - Suppes, Patrick, 1982 (Folder 33)
  - Swarthmore College, 1967-1970 (Folder 34)
  - Sweezy, Alan, 1949 (Folder 35)
  - Sweezy, Paul M., 1957-1958 (Folder 36)
  - Swoboda, Alexander K., 1972-1974 (Folder 37)
  - Tagliacozzo, Giorgio, 1939-1942 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Taguchi, Yoshihiro, 1957-1971 (Folder 2)
  - Takata, Yasuma, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Takikawa, Yukitoki (Kyoto University), 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Tanaka, Kinji, 1955-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Tarshis, Lorie, 1942-1970 (Folder 6)
  - Tasugi, Kiso, 1955-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Tatemoto, Masahiro, 1959-1970 (Folder 8)
  - Taubmann, Juda, 1936-1939 (Folder 9)
  - Taylor, Horace, 1934-1953 (Folder 10)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America College Retirement Equities Fund, 1939-1981 (Folder 11)
  - Technology and Culture, 1959-1965 (Folder 12)
  - Texas A & M University, 1968 (Folder 13)
  - Thirlby, G. F., 1942-1948 (Folder 14)
  - Thompson, J. M., 1934 (Folder 15)
  - Thorelli, Hans B., 1954-1958 (Folder 16)
  - Thorp, Willard L. (Merrill Center for Economics), 1953-1975 (Folder 17)
  - Thurn, Max, 1967-1968 (Folder 18)
  - Till, Irene, 1948-1957 (Folder 19)
  - Timberg, Sigmund, 1952 (Folder 20)
  - Tinbergen, J., 1949-1957 (Folder 21)
  - Tintner, Gerhard, 1937-1982 (Folder 22)
  - Tobin, James, 1963-1980 (Folder 23)
  - Todorovich, Miro M., 1973 (Folder 24)
  - Tokyo Colloquium (Shuzo Takeshita), 1972-1982 (Folder 25)
  - Toyo Keizai Shinposha, 1967 (Folder 26)
  - Travaglini, Volrico (Economia internazionale), 1946-1956 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Trevoux, F., 1959-1962 (Folder 2)
  - Triffin, Robert. Includes and correspondence with William J. Fellner
    - 1953-1967 (Folder 3)
    - 1968-1982 (Folder 4)
  - Troeller, Ruth R., 1967-1968 (Folder 5)
  - Trow, Martin, 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Tsiang, Sho-Chien, 1958-1981 (Folder 7)
  - Tsuru, Shigeto, 1955-1982 (Folder 8)
  - Tucker, Robert, 1963 (Folder 9)
  - Tugendhat, George, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Turvey, Ralph, 1952-1953 (Folder 11)
  - Twentieth Century Fund (J. Frederic Dewhurst), 1934-1962 (Folder 12)
  - Tydings, Millard E., 1949 (Folder 13)
  - Tyson, Leonard S., 1950-1956 (Folder 14)
  - Uchida, Yukio (Research Institute of Telecommunications and Economics), 1970 (Folder 15)
  - Ueno, Takashi, 1972 (Folder 16)
  - Ullman, Joseph L., 1942-1952 (Folder 17)
  - Unger, Frederich and Annie, 1939-1944 (Folder 18)
  - United Nations, 1947-1979 (Folder 19)
  - United States Associates of the International Chamber of Commerce (George T. Ross), 1947-1948 (Folder 20)
  - United States Council of the International Chamber of Commerce, 1968 (Folder 21)
  - United States Information Agency, 1973 (Folder 22)
  - United States. Congress. Includes correspondence with Don D. Humphrey
    - 1946-1957 (Folder 23)
    - 1958-1962 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - 1963-1982 (Folder 2)
  - United States. Department of Commerce, 1975-1977 (Folder 3)
  - United States. Department of Commerce. Bureau of the Census, 1958-1974 (Folder 4)
  - United States. Department of Labor, 1942-1943. Includes notes (Folder 5)
  - United States. Department of State, 1955-1977 (Folder 6)
  - United States. Department of the Teasury (Seymour E. Harris, Henry C. Wallich), 1964-1977. Includes correspondence with George P. Shultz and Paul A. Volker (Folder 7)
  - United States. Embassy (Japan), 1955 (Folder 8)
  - Universidad Autonoma de Madrid, 1971 (Folder 9)
  - Universitat Bonn, 1963 (Folder 10)
  - Universitat des Saarlandes, 1959 (Folder 11)
  - Universitat Graz, 1977 (Folder 12)
  - Universitat Hamburg, 1962-1963 (Folder 13)
  - Universitat Mainz, 1959-1960 (Folder 14)
  - Universitat Munchen, 1959 (Folder 15)
  - Universitat Trier (Gerard Radnitzky), 1977-1979 (Folder 16)
  - Universitat Wien, 1948-1973 (Folder 17)
  - University of Buffalo, 1952-1963 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1935-1937 (Folder 2)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1934-1947 (Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago, 1953-1973 (Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1944-1980 (Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago Round Table, 1950 (Folder 6)
  - University of Colorado, 1966 (Folder 7)
  - University of Delaware, 1974 (Folder 8)
  - University of Glasgow, 1975-1976 (Folder 9)
  - University of Hawaii, 1967 (Folder 10)
  - University of Illinois, 1941 (Folder 11)
  - University of Islamabad, 1976 (Folder 12)
  - University of Michigan, 1935-1962 (Folder 13)
  - University of Minnesota, 1968 (Folder 14)
  - University of Nebraska Press, 1969-1979 (Folder 15)
  - University of North Carolina, 1958 (Folder 16)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1956-1982 (Folder 17)
  - University of Rochester, 1942-1957 (Folder 18)
  - University of South Carolina, 1972 (Folder 19)
  - University of South Florida, 1972 (Folder 20)
  - University of Southern California, 1950-1951 (Folder 21)
  - University of Texas, 1963-1964 (Folder 22)
  - University of Washington, 1949 (Folder 23)
  - University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee (John H. Smith), 1962 (Folder 24)
  - Uri, Pierre, 1963-1964 (Folder 25)
  - Vakil, C. N., 1955-1967 (Folder 26)
  - Van den Haag, Ernest, 1964 (Folder 27)
  - Van Dewater, John, 1950 (Folder 28)
  - Van Sickle, John V., 1947-1961 (Folder 29)
  - Vandenhoeck and Ruprecht, 1961-1971 (Folder 30)
  - Vanek, Jaroslav, 1962 (Folder 31)
  - Vassar College, 1969 (Folder 32)
  - Vaughan, Floyd Lamar and Wilma, 1946-1956 (Folder 33)
  - Vecchio, Gustavo del, 1949-1950 (Folder 34)
  - Veit, Otto, 1953-1979 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Veith, Ilza, 1949-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Velasco, Gustavo R., 1950-1975 (Folder 3)
  - Villard, Henry H., 1952 (Folder 4)
  - Villey, Daniel, 1960-1963 (Folder 5)
  - Viner, Jacob and Ellen, 1935-1972 (Folder 6)
  - Viteles, Harry, 1951-1954 (Folder 7)
  - Vito, Francesco, 1938-1956 (Folder 8)
  - Voegelin, Eric, 1934-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Voigt, Fritz, 1961-1971 (Folder 10)
  - Volcker, Paul A., 1979 (Folder 11)
  - Volger, Gernot, 1972-1973 (Folder 12)
  - W.W. Norton and Company, 1971-1975 (Folder 13)
  - Wagner, Helmut R., 1975-1982. (Folder 14)
    See also SUBJECT FILE, Alfred Schutz
  - Wagner, Valentin F., 1951 (Folder 15)
  - Walker, Ross G., 1947 (Folder 16)
  - Wallace, Donald, 1939 (Folder 17)
  - Wallich, Henry C., 1969-1981 (Folder 18)
  - Wallis, W. Allen, 1935-1978 (Folder 19)
  - Walter, Ingo, 1976 (Folder 20)
  - Walter Eucken Institut (Alfred Bosch, Edith Eucken-Erdsiek), 1954-1978 (Folder 21)
  - Wangenheim, Eberhard von, 1966-1970 (Folder 22)
  - Watanabe, Taro, 1970-1978 (Folder 23)
  - Watanabe, Yukiro, 1978 (Folder 24)
  - Watkins, Myron W., 1939-1950 (Folder 25)
  - Watrin, Christian, 1972-1980 (Folder 26)
  - Weber, Wilhelm, 1971-1979 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Weiller, Jean, 1941-1977 (Folder 2)
  - Weinhard, Karl, 1949-1951 (Folder 3)
  - Weintraub, Sidney and Sheila, 1943-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Weinwurm, Ernst H., 1939-1942 (Folder 5)
  - Weisbrod, Burton, 1973 (Folder 6)
  - Weisskopf, Victor F., 1943-1979 (Folder 7)
  - Weisskopf, Walter A., 1939-1974 (Folder 8)
  - Welter, Erich and Hilde, 1955-1982 (Folder 9)
  - Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv, 1951-1975 (Folder 10)
  - Wertheimer, Michael, 1970-1971 (Folder 11)
  - Wesleyan University, 1981 (Folder 12)
  - West, Robert L., 1966 (Folder 13)
  - Western Reserve University, 1945 (Folder 14)
  - Wheeler, John A., 1968 (Folder 15)
  - Whitaker, Kenneth, 1974 (Folder 16)
  - Whitman, Marina v. N., 1967-1972 (Folder 17)
  - Whitney, Simon N., 1980 (Folder 18)
  - Whittlesey, Charles Raymond, 1952-1962 (Folder 19)
  - Wiener Institut fur Internationale Wirtschaftsvergleiche (Friedrich Levcik, Franz Nemschak). Includes correspondence with the Ford Foundation
    - 1969 (Folder 20)
    - 1970 (Folder 21)
    - 1971 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - 1972 (Folder 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Folder 3)
    - 1975 (Folder 4)
    - 1975-1977 (re Workshops on East-West European Economic Interaction) (Folder 5-10)
    - 1976-1977 (Folder 11)
    - 1977 (Folder 12)
    - 1978-1979 (Folder 13)
  - Wieser, Kurt, 1955-1958 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Wieser, Wolfgang, 1954-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Wilcox, Clair and Marcia (Swarthmore College), 1951-1971 (Folder 3)
  - Willett, Thomas D., 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Willgerodt, Hans, 1953-1976 (Folder 5)
  - William H. Donner Foundation, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - William Hodge and Company, 1936-1963 (Folder 7)
  - William Volker Fund, 1958-1960 (Folder 8)
  - Williams, John Burr, 1967 (Folder 9)
  - Williams, John H., 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Williams, P. M., 1972 (Folder 11)
  - Williams, Richard H., 1938-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Williamson, Harold, 1939 (Folder 13)
  - Williamson, John H., 1971-1976 (Folder 14)
  - Willis, George H., 1967 (Folder 15)
  - Willis, H. Parker, 1934-1935 (Folder 16)
  - Wilson, Thomas, 1976-1977 (Folder 17)
  - Winch, Donald, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Winternitz, Emanuel, 1936-1979 (Folder 19)
  - Wirlandner, Stefan, 1977 (Folder 20)
  - Wirtschaftspolitik, 1975 (Folder 21)
  - Wirtschaftsrat der CDU (Herbert B. Schmidt), 1966-1968 (Folder 22)
  - Wirtschaftswoche, 1971 (Folder 23)
  - Wisconsin State Journal, 1949 (Folder 24)
  - Wold, Herman, 1957-1978 (Folder 25)
  - Wolfers, A., 1934 (Folder 26)
  - Wolman, Leo, 1952 (Folder 27)
  - Woolley, Herb, 1948-1949 (Folder 28)
  - Worcester, Dean, Jr., 1945 (Folder 29)
  - Wright, David McCord, 1951-1964 (Folder 30)
  - Wright, Ivan, 1934 (Folder 31)
  - Wriston, Walter B., 1972 (Folder 32)
  - Yale Economics Club, 1934-1941 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Yale University, 1941 (Folder 2)
  - Yale University Press, 1945 (Folder 3)
  - Yamanaka, Toyokuni, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Yasuba, Yasukichi, 1970-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Young, John Parke, 1968 (Folder 6)
  - Young Women's Christian Associations, Buffalo, New York, 1945-1946 (Folder 7)
  - Zaner, Richard.
  - Zassenhaus, Herbert K., 1938 (Folder 8)
  - Zebot, Cyril A., 1953-1954 (Folder 9)
  - Zeitschrift fur das gesamte Kreditwesen, 1959 (Folder 10)
  - Zeitschrift fur den Dialog, 1967 (Folder 11)
  - Zeitschrift fur die gesamte Staatswissenschaft, 1952 (Folder 12)
  - Zeitschrift fur Nationalokonomie, 1937 (Folder 13)
  - Zeuthen, Frederik, 1947-1958 (Folder 14)
  - Zijlstra, J., 1968-1972 (Folder 15)
  - Zimbler, Liane, 1941 (Folder 16)
  - Zimbler, Otto, 1938-1951 (Folder 17)
  - Zinke, George W., 1935-1966 (Folder 18)
  - Zolotas, Xenophon, 1940-1982 (Folder 19)
  - Zonneveld, H. van, 1969 (Folder 20)
- NOTES, 1917-1983.
  See also INDEX CARD FILE
  - General
    - Notebooks
      - Undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 2)
      - 1930-1960 (Folder 3)
      - 1931 (Folder 4)
      - 1933-1935 (Folder 5)
      - 1935 (Folder 6)
      - 1962-1982 (Folder 7)
      - 1977 (Folder 8)
    - Notes and quotes to be used in articles and speeches, mainly on international finance, n.d. (Folder 9-11)
    - Notes found in Fritz Machlup's home office and briefcase at the time of his death in 1983 (Folder 12-13)
  - Agriculture (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Anthropology (Folder 2)
  - Balance of payments (Folder 3-5)
  - Banks (Folder 6)
  - Competition (Folder 7)
  - Cost theory (Folder 8)
  - Dollar shortage (Folder 9)
  - Douglas' theory of wages (Folder 10)